<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MocaccinoOS – Download and install</title>
    <link>https://www.mocaccino.org/docs/desktop/install/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Download and install on MocaccinoOS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://www.mocaccino.org/docs/desktop/install/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Download</title>
      <link>https://www.mocaccino.org/docs/desktop/install/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mocaccino.org/docs/desktop/install/download/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Official releases can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mocaccinoOS/mocaccino/releases&#34;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;login&#34;&gt;Login&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The live images should log you into the graphical environment automatically. If you require a password for the default user:&lt;br&gt;
Default username and password is &lt;em&gt;mocaccino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Installation</title>
      <link>https://www.mocaccino.org/docs/desktop/install/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mocaccino.org/docs/desktop/install/installation/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Installing MocaccinoOS Using the Calamares Installer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide walks you through installing MocaccinoOS to your hard drive using the Calamares graphical installer. It applies to all editions of MocaccinoOS, including KDE Plasma, GNOME, XFCE, and MATE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boot into the Live Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After downloading the MocaccinoOS ISO and writing it to a USB stick, boot your computer from the USB. You’ll be greeted with the live session desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, you can explore the live environment or go straight to installation.
2. Launch the Calamares Installer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look for the installer icon labeled “Install MocaccinoOS” on the desktop or in the application menu. Click to start the installation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]
3. Choose Your Language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select your preferred language for the installation process. This choice will also set the default language for the installed system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click Next to continue.
4. Select Your Location and Time Zone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose your region and time zone. This sets your system clock and affects time/date display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click Next to proceed.
5. Keyboard Layout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose the keyboard layout that matches your hardware or preferences. You can test your keyboard in the input field provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click Next when ready.
6. Partition Your Disk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this step, you choose how to partition your hard drive. You typically have three options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Erase disk – Wipes the entire disk and installs MocaccinoOS.

Replace a partition – Overwrites an existing partition.

Manual partitioning – Advanced option for custom layouts.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ake sure to back up important data before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click Next once you’ve made your choice.
7. Create a User Account&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter your full name, desired username, and password. Optionally, choose to log in automatically or use the same password for the administrator account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click Next to continue.
8. Summary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review the installation summary. Double-check partition choices and user information. If everything looks correct, click Install.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confirm that you want to proceed when prompted.
9. Installation Progress&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calamares will now install MocaccinoOS to your disk. This can take a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]
10. Installation Complete&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the process is finished, you’ll see a confirmation screen. You can choose to restart immediately or stay in the live session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[screenshot]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remove the installation media when prompted and reboot.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
